What do you see when you look at me?
The Equalizer is a thriller, action, crime film directed by Antoine Fuqua.
McCall believes he has put his mysterious past behind him and
dedicated himself to beginning a new, quiet life.
But when he meets Teri, a young girl under the control of ultra-violent
Russian gangsters, he can’t stand idly by – he has to help her.
Armed with hidden skills that allow him to serve vengeance against anyone who would brutalize the helpless,
McCall comes out of his self-imposed retirement and finds his desire for justice reawakened.
If someone has a problem, if the odds are stacked against them, if
they have nowhere else to turn, McCall will help.
He is The Equalizer.
Robert McCall, played by Denzel Washington.
Teddy, played by Marton Csokas.
Teri, played by Chloë Grace Moretz.
Masters, played by David Harbour.
Mandy, played by Haley Bennett.
Brian Plummer, played by Bill Pullman.
The Equalizer is a 2014 American vigilante action-thriller film
directed by Antoine Fuqua and written by Richard Wenk.
It is based on the 1980s TV series of the same title and the
first of three films starring Denzel Washington.
The cast includes Marton Csokas, Chloë Grace Moretz,
David Harbour, Bill Pullman and Melissa Leo.
Washington plays Robert McCall, a retired Marine and former DIA officer, who reluctantly returns to
action to protect a teenage trafficking victim from the members of the Russian mafia.
Principal photography took place in Massachusetts
from May 2013 to September 2013.
The world premiere for The Equalizer was held at 2014 Toronto International Film Festival
on September 7, 2014, and it was released worldwide on September 26, 2014.
The film received mixed reviews from critics and
grossed $192.3 million worldwide.
The sequels, The Equalizer 2 and The Equalizer 3, were released on
July 20, 2018, and September 1, 2023, respectively.
The film explores themes of assassin, corruption, hitman, call girl, sadism.
The tone is dark and intense.